The Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu
（ナルト）も　もしかして。
（カカシ）あれは…。
I-Is that...?!
That's the...!
（八尾）間違いねえ。
There's no mistaking it.
うっ！
（九喇嘛）ああ　あれが…。
Yeah…
That's…
（九喇嘛）十尾だ。
The Ten Tails!
魔像の悪いチャクラは
消えたはずなのに。
But I thought the Statue's evil chakra
had disappeared!
クソ！　やられた！
Damn it! They got us!
あれに　そんな感情も
概念もねえよ。
That thing doesn't have
that kind of emotion of feeling!
感知はできねえ。
It can't be sensed.
ありゃな　ふだん土や水
空気に感じるものと同じ。
It's Natural Energy itself.
It's the same as that which
circulates around the world,
この世界を循環している
自然エネルギーそのものだ。
that you can feel in
the soil, water, and the air.
仙人モードになるときと
同じコツでやりゃ　話は別だが。
It would be a different story
if you tried it
while engaged in Sage Mode though.
そっか！
あれが自然エネルギーだってんなら→
Got it!
So if you say he's all Nature Energy,
どれほどのもんか
確かめてやんよ！
then I can check him out!
やめとけ　ナルト。
どのみち　そんなことしても…。
Forget it, Naruto…
Even if you tried something like that…
All you'll see is just
how immeasurable it is.
計り知れねえってのが
はかれるだけだ。
ヘッ…　笑えねえ。
You're not kidding.
（マダラ）十尾復活までの間に→
I had planned to capture them
before the Ten Tails revived, but...
やつらを捕まえる
つもりだったんだがな。
意外にやるな。
They're pretty good.
（オビト）すぐに　無限月読の
儀式を始めたい。
I want to start the Infinite Tsukuyomi
ritual immediately.
あの大幻術は
月を呼ぶまでに時間がかかる。
That Great Genjutsu requires time
to summon the moon.
やつらは　術の邪魔になる。
They will interfere with the jutsu.
先に　魔像の力で処理したほうが
スムーズに事が運ぶ。
Things will go more smoothly
if we use the Statue's power
to get rid of them first.
違うか？
Don't you agree?
マダラ…　あんたは　十尾の力を
使ってみたいだけだろ。
Madara…
You just want to test
the Ten Tails' power, don't you?
だから　わざと…。
That's why you deliberately...
まるで　子供だな。
You're like a child.
違うな。　ガキってのは
落ち着きのないせっかちのことだ。
No.
Brats are impatient, touchy fools.
（八尾）おい　すんげえの来てるぜ。
本当にやれんのかよ！？
Hey… Here comes a big one.
You think we can really do this?
（九喇嘛）怖えからって→
Don't think you can hide
under your tentacles
タコツボに　ずっと
隠れてられると思うなよ。
'cuz you're scared!
と　その前に　ガイってのを渡せ。
But first, hand me Guy over there.
あとで回復させといてやる。
I'll heal him later.
そっちの　ナルトとカカシもだ。
おう。
And that Naruto and Kakashi too!
Yeah!
ほらよ。
（ガイ）うわ～！
Here you go!
いいか　まずは距離をとって
あれの出方を見ろ。
Listen up.
First, we keep our distance
and see what move he makes!
その出方に合わせて
攻撃をかわし→
Then we'll counter the attack
近距離で　でかい一発をくらわす。
さっき言ったとおりだ。
and hit him with a big blow
as close as we can get.
Just like I said earlier!
九尾　まるで隊長だな。
Nine Tails,
you're acting like a captain.
あっ？　文句あるか！
Huh? You got a problem with that?!
いや　なんだか嬉しくてね。
Nope…
In fact, I feel kind of happy!
ヘッ…。
そういうのは…
勝ってからにしやがれ！
That line...
Save it for after we've won!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
《意外に速え》
It's surprisingly fast…
《出方を見るもなにも
いきなりか》
There wasn't any time to
observe its moves!
《クソッ》
Damn it!
Now! Eight-O!
（キラービー）今だ　八っつぁん！
（２人）連続　尾獣玉！
Tailed Beast...
Bomb Barrage!
避ける必要もない。
There's no need to dodge.
十尾の力は　なるべく
温存しておきたいんだがな。
I want to preserve Ten Tails' power
as much as possible.
これは？
This is…
やべえな。
…not good!
頼んだぜ！
It's all on you now!
しぶといやつらだ。
Persistent lot!
おい　ナルト　もしかして…。
Hey, Naruto, don't tell me...
慌てんなって　ゲキマユ先生。
Don't worry Bushier Brow Sensei.
ナイス　コントロールだ　ナルト。
Nice control, Naruto!
いいところへ投げた。
You got them in nice and close!
《十尾に意識をかけすぎたか》
We focused too much on Ten Tails.
《足１本分はすみません
そろそろいきますよ！》
Sorry about the one leg.
But here we go!
神威！
Kamui!
Yeah!
おお！
確かにタコ足１本分→
It just looks like one octopus leg
got left behind, but...
向こうへ飛ばしそこねた
みてえだけどな。
ビーさん　八尾。
Bee! Eight Tails!
♪♪「タコツボ作戦　卑怯ですみません」
Operation Octopus Pot!
Sorry it's a mean and cowardly plot!
その目玉にぶち込んでやる！
I'm gonna smash this
into his eyeball!
《当たれ！》
Get him!
あっ。
Huh?!
クッ。
上にもハエが２匹いるぞ。
There are two flies above us as well…
《十尾の尾》
The Ten Tails' tail?!
Naruto!
ナルト。
((うっ！
（オビト）カカシ！))
Kakashi!
《ナルト　お前は俺とよく似ている》
Naruto, you really are
a lot like me.
ぐあっ！
That's right,
you're just younger than me.
《そう　お前は俺より
まだ若いだけだ。　いずれ…》
Eventually…
ぐぁ～っ！
《すまねえ　八っつぁんに
ビーのおっちゃん》
Forgive me, Eight-O and Octopops!
また影分身か。
Another Shadow Clone, huh?
クッ。
イテッ。
ふぅ。
Kurama!
九喇嘛！　こんなときに
なんで崩れんだよ！
How can you fall apart
at a time like this?!
約８分。　前よりは長持ちしたが
これが限界だな。
That was about eight minutes.
It's longer than before,
but that's the limit.
I'm going to have to infuse
and build up my chakra.
いったんわしは
チャクラを練り　溜める。
クッ…　しゃあねえか。
Guess we have no choice.
That hurts, fool. Ya fool!
痛えぜ　バカ野郎　この野郎。
（八尾）ビー　俺も少し休む　限界だ。
Bee!
I'm going to rest a bit too.
I'm also at my limit.
回復は　まだか…？
I can't get healed yet?
《八尾ほど　大きいものを
出し入れするのは→
Pulling something as massive
as Eight Tails in and out
sure comes with
a correspondingly large cost.
負担がでかいね。　すぐバテる》
I'm drained already.
八尾と九尾は
いったんチャクラ切れのようだな。
Seems Eight Tails and Nine Tails
have run out of chakra for now.
You favorite Shadow Clone Jutsu?
お得意の影分身か？
禁術の高等忍術とて
同じ無能が増えたところで。
It may be forbidden high-level ninjutsu,
but just increasing
the number of losers won't--
I'm not a loser!
俺は無能じゃねえ！
（カカシ）よせ　ナルト。
Stop, Naruto!
これ以上　チャクラを等分割させる
影分身は意味がない。
It's meaningless to
create Shadow Clones
that will divide your chakra
even more.
They might be useful as diversions,
but not for decisive hits.
陽動に使えても
決定打にはならない。
お前が倒れたら
この戦争は負ける。
And if you go down...
we lose this war.
しょせんは烏合の衆。
You were always just
a motley crew anyway.
Huh?!
あっ？
う…　う　う　うごう　うごう。
M-M-Motley crew?
やはり無能だ。
Like I said, you're incompetent.
頭数だけ増やしても
その中身がまったくなければ→
He's saying that it's pointless to
merely increase the number of heads...
if they're all empty.
無意味だと言っているんだ。
俺もお前も
しょせん無力な忍だ。
You and I are both powerless shinobi.
You...
お前も…　いや　誰でもいずれ→
no, I should say everyone…
俺のようになるのだからな。
will eventually end up like me.
俺は　てめえみてえにはならねえ！
I'll never end up like you!
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
何度も言ってんだろ！
俺がなりてえのは火影だ！
My dream is to become the Hokage!
心配するな　すべてうまくいく。
Don't worry.
Everything will go as planned.
There is no shinobi jutsu mightier
than the Infinite Tsukuyomi.
無限月読に勝る忍の術はない。
この術の中で
お前を火影にしておいてやる。
I'll make you Hokage inside this jutsu.
だから　この世界ごと消えろ！
So…
Just disappear along
with the rest of this world!
クッ…　チッ。
What the…?
（カカシ）これは！？
外れた？　わざとか？
Did it miss? On purpose?
ようやくか。
About time!
（ヒアシ）カカシ　ガイ！　待たせたな！
Kakashi! Guy!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
（いの）白眼のサポートで
ドンピシャの心転身を→
I can't believe he shook off
my Byakugan-aided, spot-on Mind Transfer
in just two seconds!
たったの２秒ではじくなんて！
それでもデカブツの攻撃ポイントは
ずらせた。　上出来だ。
But you still succeeded in shifting
that large thing's aim off target.
Good work!
（ヒナタ）ナルト君　大丈夫？
おう！
Are you all right, Naruto?
Yeah!
（キバ）ヒナタの前だからって
強がんなくてもいいぜ　ナルト！
You don't have to act tough
in front of Hinata, Naruto!
（みんな）蟲邪民具の術！
Beetle Jamming Jutsu!
（みんな）霧隠れの術！
Hidden Mist Jutsu!
（チョウジ）来たよ　ナルト。
We're here, Naruto!
（シカマル）よし　これで簡単には
感知されねえだろ。
All right, we won't be
so easily detectable now!
（カルイ）ビー様
思ったより大丈夫そうね。
Lord Bee! You're in better shape
than I expected!
（オモイ）ビー様…　重傷じゃないっすか。
Lord Bee! You look seriously wounded!
オモイ　お前は　心配しすぎだ。
Omoi, you worry too much!
（リー）ガイ先生　まさか昼虎を。
リー。
Guy Sensei, don't tell me
you used Hirudora?!
Lee!
（サイ）遅くなりました　カカシ隊長。
I'm sorry we're late, Captain Kakashi.
サクラちゃん　まずは。
Sakura, first off...!
（サクラ）わかってる。
I know!
《シカク：感知水球が
原形をとどめてねえな　もはや》
The Sensory Water Sphere won't
maintain its original shape.
We better...!
（シカク）いのいち　青…　状況確認。
Inoichi! Ao! Confirm the situation!
（いのいち）よし。
（青）オーケー。
- Roger!
- Okay!
（ダルイ）第１部隊　到着。
First Company has arrived!
（黄ツチ）第２部隊も到着だ。
Second Company has also arrived!
第３部隊　到着。
Third Company has arrived!
第４部隊　到着。
Fourth Company has arrived!
（ミフネ）第５部隊も同じく。
Fifth Company has also arrived!
（シズネ）医療部隊も来ました。
The Medical Unit's here too!
（シー）感知部隊　到着。
Sensory Unit has arrived!
それで隠れたつもりか。
Nice try hiding, but...
（テマリ）風遁　風切りの術。
Wind Style!
Art of the Gust Blade!
これで　もう
烏合の衆ってのじゃねえ。
We're not a motley crew anymore!
今　ここにあるのは
忍連合軍の術だ。
Here is the Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu!
The world's greatest, most invincible,
super-duper ninjutsu, you know!
超すげえ　忍史上
最高　最強の忍術だってばよ。
無限月読に勝る術だ。　覚えとけ。
A jutsu that trumps
the Infinite Tsukuyomi. Remember that!
忍連合の術か。
The Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu, eh?
Don't you think that's a bit of stretch?
こじつけも　いいところだ。
この術で　お前らを止める！
We're going to stop you two
with this jutsu!
違う。　お前らがここで
俺たちを止めようが→
You're wrong.
Why won't you realize that
it's meaningless for you to stop us here?
無意味なことに　なぜ気づかない？
その術とて　この戦争のあとには
もろく崩れ→
After this war,
even that jutsu will disintegrate…
そちら側の誰かが　また俺たちと→
Then someone from your side
will attempt to do
同じことをするようになる。
exactly what we're doing now.
この世界でもがいても勝ちはない。
There is no victory,
no matter how much you struggle.
クッ…　この世界に希望など
どこにもないと　もう知れ！
Get it through your head.
There's no such thing as hope
anywhere in this world.
どうだろうが→
I don't care!
あることにする。
I'll make sure there's hope!
戦争中にあるないと言い合うのも
無意味だ。
It's meaningless to argue
whether there is or isn't
something during a war.
そろそろ決着をつけるか。
How about we settle this now?
意見が分かれたときは
多数決ってのが決まりだろ→
When there's a difference of opinion,
isn't the usual way majority rule?
だいたい　どうする？
So what do we do?
いい案だ。　なら　１人残らず
消してからにしよう。
That's a good suggestion.
Then…
We'll call it after
we've erased all of you
そして…。
やっぱ　そうくるか。
And...
I knew you'd say that.
けど…。
But…
（オビト／ナルト）この世界は…。
This world…
終わらせる！
終わらせねえ！
- will end!
- will not end!
いくぞ　みんな。
最終決戦だ！
Let's go, everyone!
This is the final deciding battle!
（みんな）お～！
散。
Scatter!
《シカク：時間稼ぎ　よくやったナルト》
Thanks for buying us
some time, Naruto.
作戦を練る時間　取れた？
Did you have enough time
to come up with a strategy?
Thanks to you, I was able to
relay it to everyone!
《いや　おかげで　作戦を→
みんなに伝える時間が
きっちり取れた》
《カカシから面の男が→
Kakashi told us the masked man
is Obito Uchiha.
うちはオビトだったと聞いても
驚く暇もないよ。
But there's no time to be shocked.
この戦い　先手を取り続け
反撃のスキを与えん》
For this fight, we need to take
and maintain the upper hand
and not give them
any opportunity to counter!
《情報からして
敵には立派な眼がある。
According to the intel we received,
our enemy has impressive eyes.
まずは　目くらましで
動きを鈍らせ　視界を潰す》
First, we'll impede their movement
by destroying their vision.
《雲隠れの衆》
The Hidden Cloud!
雷遁　雷光柱！
Lightning Style!
Flash Pillar!
Gale Style! Laser Circus.
嵐遁　レイザーサーカス。
I see…
（マダラ）なるほど…
本当の狙いは　十尾の目潰しか。
Their true aim is to blind Ten Tails!
《シカク：次は少し前の
霧隠れの霧と邪民具の蟲。
With the two jutsu from earlier,
the Hidden Mist's Mist
and the Beetle Jamming...
Along with the large volume
of airborne dust
更に　嵐遁でできた多量の土煙を
気流にのせ操り…》
stirred up by the Gale Style right now...
《砂隠れの衆！　今だ！》
The Hidden Sand, now!
（みんな）風遁　気流乱舞！！
Wind Style: Air Current Dance!
We'll not just destroy
their vision completely,
《シカク：視界を完璧に潰しつつ→
but thwart them from
even sensing us at all.
こちらの姿と気配を
とらえられなくする。
And since their sheer bulk
prevents them from hiding...
あちらは　でかい分
隠れようがないからな。
we'll be able to take
full advantage of the situation.
その条件は
十分に活かさせてもらう》
We only revealed our jutsu
to him a short while ago,
《テマリ：他里の術を教えたのは
ついこの前なのに→
and he's already incorporating them
into the battle plan!
すぐに
実戦に取り入れやがるとはな。
あのシカマルのオヤジだけはあるか》
Leave it to Shikamaru's dad,
like father like son!
This makes it impossible to sense them.
感知も無理だな…　これじゃ。
We'll wipe them all out with
a Ten Tails' attack!
十尾の攻撃で　なぎ払えばいい。
The Hidden Stone,
proceed immediately!
《岩隠れの衆　すぐに次だ！》
わかっておる！
We know!
Earth Style: Vast Mobile Core!
土遁　大地動核！！
《シカク：感覚を奪った次は
体の自由を奪う》
After shutting down their senses,
we'll immobilize them!
くっ。
《十尾を落としたら
すぐに石灰だ》
As soon as we bring down
the Ten Tails, pour in quicklime!
（みんな）溶遁　石灰凝の術！！
- Lava Style: Quicklime Jutsu!
《霧隠れの衆　続け！》
Hidden Mist! You're up next!
（みんな）水遁　水弾の術！！
- Water Style: Water Bomb Jutsu!
We'll add water to the mix,
《シカク：更に水を一緒に注ぎ
石灰と水を一気にカクハンさせる》
and rapidly stir up the quicklime!
Hidden Leaf! Let's finish this!
《木ノ葉隠れの衆　仕上げだ！》
猿飛一族のみんな　いくぞ！
Sarutobi Clan members!
Let's go!
火遁　豪炎の術！！
Fire Style: Majestic Flame Jutsu!
And we'll dry it with the heat
from the Fire Style…
《シカク：それを
火遁の熱で乾かし…》
Let it set and immobilize it!
（シカク）固めて　止める。
Unbelievable.
信じられん。
あの五里の忍共が→
Who would've thought,
that the ninja from the five villages
could work so cooperatively.
ここまでの連携を
やってみせるとはな…。
Unless we stop the Ten Tails,
《シカク：十尾を止めないことには
オビトとマダラを狙うチャンスもない。
we don't have a chance
to go after Obito or Madara.
十尾は　やつらにとって
術を発動させるための道具。
頭である
その２人の術者をたたけば→
無限月読とやらは
発動しないはずだ。
ただし
十尾の力を抑えられる時間は→
あまりないと思ったほうがいい。
マダラは　物理攻撃以外　効かない。
体術スキルのある忍は　マダラにかかれ！
オビトは
すべての技と術をすり抜けるが→
情報では　５分間だけだそうだ。
医療部隊と連携しつつ
５分以上　攻撃の手を緩めるな！
ナルト…
そう　今こそ　お前の言う…》
忍連合の術だってばよ！
哀れだな。
ああ…。
（オビト）やつらのすがっている
希望などは存在しない。
今となっては
やつらの存在とて　それと同じ。
（マダラ）十尾も　頃合いのようだ。
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
≫豆助
きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のアレよ？
＜　その野菜とは…？＞